Guide to the California Bean Growers' Warehouse Corporation Records, 1918-1947 JL003
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
California Bean Growers' Warehouse Corporation Records,
1918-1947
JL003
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
6.0 Linear feet
California Bean Growers' Warehouse Corporation.
Scope and Content
The collection is listed in two series. The first consists of minute books, by laws, legal papers, correspondence, leases and account books of the California Bean Growers' Warehouse Corporation, covering the years of its existence, 1922-1947. The second series consists of minute books, by laws, administrative material and account books, also covering the years of its existence, 1918-1929.
The minute books are perhaps the most valuable source of information to anyone interested in a corporation of this kind. They cover, with few exceptions, the entire period of activity for both organizations, and include additional material of interest, along with the minutes of directors'and stockholders' meetings. The rest of the material seems quite complete and presents a clear picture of the entire operation of the California Bean Growers' Warehouse Corporation and Association.
Historical Note
The California Bean Growers' Warehouse Corporation was formed on September 23, 1922, with its principal office and place of business in San Francisco. From paragraph (i) of the Articles of Incorporation, “The primary purpose for the organization of this corporation is to pack, process, clean, store and warehouse the beans delivered to it by the California Bean Growers' Association, a California cooperative marketing association...” All directors were required to be stockholders of the Corporation as well as members of the Association, which was formed in 1918. The Association was dissolved in 1929 and the Corporation in 1947.
Much of the business of the Corporation centered around Pittsburg, a town in Contra Costa County, California, and the operation of warehouses, mill, wharf and fumigator.
Provenance
Transfer from Jackson Library of Business, 1979.
Access Restrictions
None.
- A. CALIFORNIA BEAN GROWERS' WAREHOUSE CORPORATION
  - DIRECTORS AND STOCKHOLDERS
    - Minutes, Oct 1922-Feb 1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, Feb 1928-Feb 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, May 1929-Jan 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, Feb 1947-Aug 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - By laws, articles of incorporation, stock permits, 1922-1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Stockholders' meeting, Feb 15, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Stock certificates, 1922-1946 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Stock ledger and journal, 1922-1939 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Consent to sale of assets, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Stock transfers, 1928-1946 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence
    - Assessment No. 2, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Notices
      - Correspondence
    - Stockholder reports, 1929-1949 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Dissolution procedures, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Notices to stockholders
      - Stockholders' consent
    - Directors' financial reports, 1928-1947 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Directors' correspondence, reports, 1929-1947 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - FINANCIAL AND GENERAL ACCOUNTS
    - Taxes: Federal Income, 1923-1935 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Taxes: Federal Income, 1936-1947 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Taxes: State Corporation Franchise, 1928-1945 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Taxes: Federal Capital Stock, 1932-1945 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Taxes: Witholding and Social Security, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - American Trust Company: loan, 1924-1947 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Bank statements, 1928-1934 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Bank statements, 1935-1942 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Bank statements, 1943-1948 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Accounts and notes receivable, 1927-1930 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - General ledger, 1922-1947 (Box 4)
    - General journal, 1922-1947 (Volume 5)
    - Cash receipt record, 1922-1947 (Volume 6)
    - Disbursement record, 1922-1947 (Volume 7)
  - REAL ESTATE AND LEASES
    - Cardinalli and Paladini: lease and claim, 1928-Aug 1930 (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - Under name of Sea Food Packing Co.
      - Land at Pittsburg
      - Lease, correspondence, option
    - Calif. Bean Growers' Warehouse Corporation -vs- Cardinalli and Paladini, Sept 1930-1932 (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - Violation of lease and option agreement of, June 1930
      - Summary of case Complaint and answers Release, March 1932
    - Inquiries regarding property of Calif. Bean Growers' Warehouse Corp., 1929-1936 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Inquiries re: property of Calif. Bean Growers' Warehouse Corp., 1937-1946 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - F.E. Booth & Co., Inc., 1930-1941 (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - Lease on property at Pittsburg
    - United Iron and Metal Co., 1932-1933 (Box 8, Folder 31)
      - Correspondence re: Pittsburg property
    - Pittsburg Canners, Inc. (J.H. Dempsey), 1933-1937 (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - Lease
      - Correspondence
    - California Scrap Iron Corporation, 1933-1942 (Box 8, Folder 33)
      - Lease
      - Correspondence
    - United State of America, 1941-1947 (Box 8, Folder 34)
      - Memoranda re: lease on property
      - Public vouchers
      - Resolutions
    - United State of America, 1942-1947 (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - Correspondence re: leases of Calif.
      - Bean Growers' Warehouse Corporation
    - General deeds, leases, contracts, 1922-1945 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Maps of property in Pittsburg (warehouse site), Suisun Bay, California (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - BUILDINGS AND EQUIPMENT
    - Pittsburg plant analysis book, 1922-1923 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Building specifications, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 39)
      - Pittsburg warehouse, mill, wharf, fumigator
    - Cahill Brothers, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 40)
      - Bidders' estimates
      - Contract
      - Correspondence
      - Notice of completion of work
    - Bodison Manufacturing Company, 1922-1924 (Box 9, Folder 41)
      - Contract-equipment for new plant at Pittsburg
    - Building repairs, 1930-1941 (Box 9, Folder 42)
      - Invoices, statements
      - Correspondence
    - Equipment sales, 1928-1931 (Box 9, Folder 43)
      - Correspondence
      - Inquiries
    - Equipment sales, 1932-1934 (Box 9, Folder 44)
      - John R. Gray & Co. (J.J. Molloy); party to whom equipment consigned Bills of sale
      - Correspondence
- B. CALIFORNIA BEAN GROWERS' ASSOCIATION
  - ADMINISTRATIVE BUSINESS
    - Minute book (including membership list 1921, reports, charts), Feb 1921-August 1923 (Volume 10)
    - Minute book (including sales averages, lists of delinquent members), Sept 1923-Nov 1928 (Volume 11)
    - Minute book, Feb-May 1929 (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - By laws, articles of incorporation, 1918-1921 (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Original marketing agreement Bean crop agreement, 1918-1919 (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - Agreements, 1919-1923 (Box 12, Folder 48)
      - Lewellyn Bean Co., 1919
      - Anglo-California Trust Co., 1919
      - Chatterton & Son, 1920
      - Calif. Bean Growers' Warehouse Corp., 1922
      - R.B. Spilavo, 1923
    - Financial reports, 1920-1928 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - Cancelled notes, 1922-1924 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Dissolution, 1928-1929 (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - GENERAL ACCOUNTS
    - Membership certificates, 1922 (Box 12, Folder 52)
    - Members' account book, 1917-1922 (Volume 13)
    - General Ledger, 1921-1929 (Volume 14)
    - Journal, 1924-1928 (Volume 15)
    - Cash receipts, 1927-1929 (Volume 16)
    - Cash disbursements, 1922-1927 (Volume 17)